Bath or shower?
泡澡还是淋浴？
How do you prefer to keep yourself clean?
你更喜欢用哪种方式清洁身体？
Whatever your daily ablutions, we know it’s important to have good personal hygiene.
无论你日常的洗浴方式是什么，我们都知道保持良好的个人卫生至关重要。
Nobody wants to smell, and nobody wants to catch your odour!
没人希望自己身上有异味，更没人愿意沾上别人的味儿！
A shower can bring you certain other benefits, but how often should we wash ourselves under a watery spray?
淋浴除了清洁，还能带来一些其他好处，但我们应该多久冲一次澡呢？
Although you might think taking a daily shower should be part of your cleaning ritual, there’s no hard and fast rule, although dermatologists agree that as a society, we shower too often.
你可能觉得每天淋浴是日常清洁的必不可少的一部分，但其实并没有硬性规定。
In fact, too much washing can deplete the vital oils in our skin.
不过皮肤科医生一致认为，在当今社会，我们洗澡的频率实在太高了。
It can waste water as well.
事实上，过度清洁会消耗皮肤中至关重要的油脂，同时还会造成水资源浪费。
However, if you have a fitness regime that causes you to sweat, a more regular sprinkle of water is recommended to stop you ponging!
但如果你有规律健身的习惯，运动后会大量出汗，那么就建议你更频繁地冲个澡，避免身上产生难闻的气味！
How often you shower is, of course, a personal choice.
多久洗一次澡当然是个人选择。
There’s nothing better than a hot, soapy scrub under the shower, and this doesn’t just have to be to clean yourself.
在花洒下用温热的肥皂水痛快地搓洗一番，这种感觉再好不过了，而且淋浴的目的也不只是为了清洁身体。
Some people enjoy a shower to help them relax, warm up or to soothe any aches and pains.
有些人喜欢通过淋浴来放松身心、让自己暖和起来，或是缓解身体的各种酸痛。
It’s also a good opportunity to wash your hair at the same time.
淋浴时也很适合顺便洗个头。
Again, though, experts say we shouldn’t shower too often because, like your skin, your hair contains essential oils that you don’t want to lose through excessive scrubbing.
不过专家同样提醒，洗头不宜过于频繁，因为和皮肤一样，头发中也含有不可或缺的油脂，过度清洗会导致这些油脂流失。
If the idea of a hot, steaming shower appeals, how about a freezing cold one instead?
如果热气腾腾的热水澡合你心意，那要不要试试冰爽的冷水澡呢？
This might be a necessity if your boiler has broken, but some people choose this option because it has many health benefits, some experts claim.
如果家里的热水器坏了，冷水澡就可能是不可避免的选择，但有专家称，有些人会主动选择冷水澡，因为它对健康大有裨益。
There is increasing evidence that braving an icy shower in the morning could keep illness at bay and may even help your brain stay sharp.
越来越多的证据表明，早上勇敢地冲个冷水澡，不仅能预防疾病，甚至还能帮助保持大脑思维敏捷。
A BBC podcast called Just One Thing with Michael Mosley, found the shock of being doused with cold water could have a positive impact on your body and brain.
迈克尔·莫斯利主持的BBC播客《一件小事》发现，身体被冷水浇透时的那种冲击感，会对身心产生积极影响。
The thought of a cold shower might not make you jump out of bed in the morning, but whatever the temperature, a splash of water will wake you up and make you feel and smell great!
想到早上要冲冷水澡，你可能对于起床这件事兴致缺缺，但无论水温冷热，冲个澡都能让你神清气爽，不仅体感舒适，身上还会香香的！